A Guide to the Barbara Whaley Bitters Hall Papers, 1975-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series VI: VIRGINIA ASSOCIATION FOR BIOLOGICAL FARMERS (VABF)
  - Reports, Proceedings of the 1983 Virginia direct marketing conference, 1983 (Box-folder Box 50 Folder 5)
  - Reports, Program inpact report for WIC farmers, 1995 (Box-folder Box 50 Folder 6)
  - Smart foods, 1994 (Box-folder Box 50 Folder 7)
  - Subject files, 1992-1997 (Box-folder Box 50 Folder 8)
  - Young Farmers, 1977-1978 (Box-folder Box 50 Folder 9)
- Series VII: Virginia Citizen's Consumer Council (VCCC)
  This series is arranged alphabetically in 6 boxes and includes annual reports, by-laws, correspondence, clippings, memoranda, minutes, reports, publications, newsletters, and speeches. The VCCC is a non-profit volunteer association founded in 1966 to promote and represent the rights and interests of the consumer in Virginia. Hall served as vice president and lobbyist from 1974-1997. The series documents the history of VCCC's contribution to Virginia consumer rights, including the enactment of the Virginia Consumer Protection Act, the establishment of local consumer protection offices, the U.S. Supreme Court decision allowing the advertising of prescription drugs, passage of a strong new-car "lemon law," successful challenges to laws restricting physician and attorney information to the public, and reform of infant formula, milk, and ground beef labeling. The series contains information on the lobbying efforts of the VCCC in the Virginia General Assembly and includes copies of bills supported by the council. Also included are copies of the VCCC newsletter entitled, "Voice of the Virginia Consumer," 1978-1997, reports on healthcare, food labeling, finance loans, and electric utilities, and speeches by members of the VCCC, including Barbara Hall, before the Virginia State Corporation Commission.
  - Anniversaries, 1993-1995 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1978-1995 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 2)
  - Board of directors, 1977-1997 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 3)
  - By-laws, 1976 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1978-1979 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1990-1997 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 7)
  - Clippings, nd (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Commissioners forum, Misc., 1992 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Commissioners forum, Publications, 1992 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Miscellaneous, 1978-1996 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 11)
  - Conferences, National Conference on Citizen Participation, 1978 (Box-folder Box 51 Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Senator Robb Forum, 1993 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 1)
  - Conferences, VCCC Consumer, 1988-1996 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1997 (Box-folder Box 52 Folder 7)
  - Diary and Food Nutrition Council, 1980-1985 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 1)
  - Dept. Agriculture and consumer services, 1979-1982 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 2)
  - Food and nutrition committee, 1979 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, 1978-1988 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, 1989-1993 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 5)
  - Memoranda, 1994-1997 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1977-1989 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1990-1997 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1991 (Box-folder Box 53 Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Voice of the Virginia Consumer, 1978-1990 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Voice of the Virginia Consumer, 1991-1997 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 3)
  - Press releases, 1978-1997 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 4)
  - Publications, Air quality-automobiles, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 5)
  - Publications, Banks, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 6)
  - Publicatioins, Coffee-funerals, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 7)
  - Publications, Consumer Education, Miscellaneous, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 54 Folder 8)
  - Publications, Consumer Education, Resource handbook, 1992-1997 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 1)
  - Publiations, Hazardous waste-telephones, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 2)
  - Reports, A consumer issue paper on electric utility restructuring, 1997 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 3)
  - Reports, The economic conditions and other factors affecting the business of making consumer finance loans, 1985 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 4)
  - Reports, Managed care, 1996 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 5)
  - Reports, Nation's high school seniors fail consumer knowledge test, 1991 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 6)
  - Reports, Regional Bell operating companies' anticompetitive and anticonsumer practices, c. 1992 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 7)
  - Reports, Rent to own, 1994 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 8)
  - Reports, Virgina auto dealers, 1994 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 9)
  - Reports, What consumers should be able to expect from food labeling, nd (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 10)
  - Reports, White paper on credit insurance, 1991 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 11)
  - Speeches, Allen, Robert, 1991 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 12)
  - Speeches, Birck, Michale J., 1991 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 13)
  - Speeches, Dalton, John, 1980 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 14)
  - Speeches, Hall, Barbara Whaley Bitters, 1979-1988 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 15)
  - Speeches, Tobias, Randall L., 1990 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 16)
  - Speeches, Umbeck, John R., nd (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 17)
  - Speeches, VCCC, 1978-1986 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 18)
  - Speeches, Willig, Sidney H., 1977 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 19)
  - Subject files, Air quality-energy taxes, 1979-1995 (Box-folder Box 55 Folder 20)
  - Subject files, Food-occupational licensing, 1977-1996 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 1)
  - Subject files, optometry-telephones, 1978-1996 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 2)
  - Subject files, Unit pricing, 1976-1980 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 3)
  - Subject files, Unit pricing, 1981 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 4)
  - Subject files, Unit pricing, 1982 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 5)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 1978-1989 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 6)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 1990-1996 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 7)
  - Virginia Pesticide Control Board, 1995 (Box-folder Box 56 Folder 8)
- Series VIII: VEPCO Customer Advisory Board
  This series is arranged alphabetically in 9 archival boxes and contains clippings, correspondence, guidelines and procedures, membership lists, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, publications, reports, and surveys. The Customer Advisory Board was created in 1980 and was comprised of eleven members chosen from state and local officials and leaders in business, industry, education, and consumer groups. Hall served on the customer advisory board from 1981-1986. The board reviewed proposed policy changes, new customer programs, service practices, customer regulations, and corporate communications. Included are reports from the board regarding bill payment options, discounts, and penalties. Also included is information form the taskforce that was formed to study the reopening of VEPCO's 12th Street Hydroelectric Plant in Richmond (Va.). The series also contains information from various Virginia General Assembly Joint Subcommittees, including committees formed to study a coal slurry pipeline in Virginia, high voltage electric transmission lines, utility diversification and deregulation, and the purchase of foreign coal by Virginia electric utility companies
  - Annual reports, 1980 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 1)
  - Board of directors, 1980-1986 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1979-1989 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 3)
  - Clippings, nd (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Edison Electric Institute, 1984 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Electrical utilities and customers, 1985-1987 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Energy and minority community, 1979 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Telephone issues for the states, 1985 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1985-1986 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 10)
  - Guidelines and procedures, Customer Advisory Board, 1980-1986 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 11)
  - Guidelines and procedures, VEPCO, 1980-1982 (Box-folder Box 57 Folder 12)
  - Memoranda, 1980-1982 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, 1984-1985 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1983-1986 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980-1986 (Box-folder Box 58 Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, Currents, 1981-1984 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, Customer Connection, 1984 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, Employee News Bulletin, 1981-1985 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, Miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, News Update, 1981 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, VEPCO, Speaking out about VEPCO, 1982-1983 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 7)
  - North Anna (Va.) Tour, 1982 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 8)
  - Notes, nd (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 9)
  - Organizational chart, 1981 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 10)
  - Port Washington (WI) Clean energy project, 1986 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 11)
  - Press releases, 1981-1985 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 12)
  - Publicatioins, 1978-1980 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 13)
  - Publications, 1981 (Box-folder Box 59 Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1981 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 1)
  - Publications, 1982 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 2)
  - Publications, 1983-1984 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 3)
  - Publications, 1985-1989 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 4)
  - Publications, nd (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 5)
  - Reports, Bill payment, 1985 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 6)
  - Reports, Customer communications, 1984 (Box-folder Box 60 Folder 7)
  - Reports, Miscellaneous, 1984-1986 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 1)
  - Reports, New structure for VEPCO, 1983 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 2)
  - Reports, Transmission lines, 1985 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 3)
  - Speeches, 1981-1983 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 4)
  - Surry Power Station (Va.) Tour, 1981 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 5)
  - Surveys, 1983 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 6)
  - Surveys, 1984 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 7)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Application for license, nd (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 8)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box-folder Box 61 Folder 9)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Proposal, 1983 (Box-folder Box 62 Folder 1)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Public hearing, 1983 (Box-folder Box 62 Folder 2)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Reports, 1983 (Box-folder Box 62 Folder 3)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Reports, 1983 (Box-folder Box 62 Folder 4)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Taks Force, Reports, 1983 (Box-folder Box 62 Folder 5)
  - Twelfth St. Hydroelectric Project Task Force, Study, 1982 (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 1)
  - U.S. Committee for Energy, 1984 (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 2)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Coal slurry pipelines, 1982 (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 3)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Coal slurry pipelines, 1983, January (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 4)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Coal slurry pipelines, 1983, July-December (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 5)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Coal slurry pipelines, 1984 (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 6)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Electric lines, 1984, May-September (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 7)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Electric lines, 1984, October-December (Box-folder Box 63 Folder 8)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Electric lines, 1985-1995 (Box-folder Box 64 Folder 1)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Foreign coal purchase, 1986 (Box-folder Box 64 Folder 2)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Foreign coal purchase, 1986 (Box-folder Box 64 Folder 3)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Utility deregulation, 1982 (Box-folder Box 64 Folder 4)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Utility deregulation, 1982 (Box-folder Box 64 Folder 5)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Utility deregulation, 1982 (Box-folder Box 65 Folder 1)
  - Virginia General Assembly- Joint Subcommittees on: Utility deregulation, 1982 (Box-folder Box 65 Folder 2)
  - Virginia State Corporation Commission, 1977 (Box-folder Box 65 Folder 3)
  - Virginia Utility Legislative Committee, 1981-1982 (Box-folder Box 65 Folder 4)
  - Biographical information, Encyclopedia of the Consumer Movement, Ephemera (Box-folder Box 66)